Dragoș Străinu

- str.dr4605@gmail.com
- +40 745 395 505 / +373 69 292 120
- github.com/strdr4605
- stackoverflow.com/users/5458200
- linkedin.com/in/dragos-strainu
- strdr4605.github.io

I am passionate about IT. I am a team player and always aim for teamwork, code review, documentation, discussions whether it is a complex project or a project just for fun. My hobbies are Hackathons and IT events, where I exchange my experience with people and learn new professional and personal skills. I also like mentoring and helping people in software engineering. I share my experience on strdr4605.github.io.

Experience

- 02.11.2020-PRESENT Amazon.com | Front End Engineer (Customer Cloud Security)
 My team owns and operates the first line of defense for Amazon's confidential customer data.
 I am responsible for a *React Native* library that encrypts and decrypts sensitive data through the network.
 I worked on integration tests for the decryption library on the Amazon website and eliminated 10 man-hours/week.
- 20.12.2018–04.09.2020 GoParrot.ai | Online Ordering Platform on Microservices Architecture I was responsible for a white-label mobile product with 7+ apps.

 I wrote automation scripts, design proposals, project documentation, and configured to development flow.

 I worked on a new version of the Platform using *React Nativel ReactJS* with 40%+ code shared between mobile and web.

 I worked on a service that synchronizes the database with partners *APIs* and reduced manual work from 1 week to 15 minutes.

A big part of my professional experience comes from **39 Hackathons** where I developed front-end/back-end/mobile apps and games. Also, I contribute to **30+ open-source projects**.

- mockingcase: I created and maintain a *Node.js* package that converts a string to mockingCaSe. Friendly documentation, unit tests, jsdoc and types for *TypeScript*. I write feature requirements and documentation, review pull requests, and guide 15+ first-time contributors on open-source.
- jump2header: I created a tool that adds markdown links to improve navigation in long README.md files on Github. Used in several popular open-source projects like exceljs and others.
- **redux-requests**: Redux addon to simplify handling of AJAX requests. I added the promise driver, set up the documentation site with docusaurus, and participated in discussions about library design.
- @goparrot/react-native-geometry-utils: I created a React Native library that exposes google maps geometry utils.
- roataway.md: Open source app, that displays real-time positions of public transport. I added features like vehicle off-route updates, render vehicles as "off", marker drift on zoom.
- **spacebook**: At NASA Hackathon 2019 my team and I created a *Progressive Web App* which shows Astronomy Picture of the Day in an infinite scroll feed. A (not perfect) app that works by these days.

Skills

Spoken Languages	Languages	Libraries/Platforms/Frameworks
Romanian - Native	JavaScript/TypeScript - Proficient	ReactJS - Proficient
English - Fluent	Version control/GIT - Proficient	React Native - Proficient
Russian - Fluent	HTML/CSS - Working knowledge	NodeJS - Working knowledge
German - Beginner	Bash - Working knowledge	Angular - Basic knowledge
	Java - Working knowledge	Selenium - Working knowledge

Education

• 01.09.2019-PRESENT Master's Degree in Computer Science, Technical University of Moldova